Sheldon Cooper之坠入疯狂...
Sheldon Cooper's descent into madness...
第二天
day two.
现在是凌晨2点25分
It's 2:25 a.m.,
我非常想去尿尿
and I feel the urge to urinate.
我通常的尿尿时间是早上7点10分
My normal urination time is 7:10 a.m.,
但看看我 现在大半夜醒着
but here I am, in the middle of the night,
努力保持清醒
struggling to keep my mind sharp
不尿湿睡衣
and my pajamas dry.
但我对现实的认知
It's only a matter of time
开始模糊也是迟早的事
before my tenuous grasp on reality fades.
我想我应该趁着还知道马桶是啥 赶紧去尿
I suppose I should pee while I still know what a toilet is.
两天前
你什么时候开始会哼歌了?
Since when do you hum songs?
你在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
- 你刚才在哼歌  - 你确定?
- You were just humming.  - Are you sure?
有时候我的大脑在运转的时候
Sometimes when my brain really gets moving,
是会发出声音的
it makes noise.
你的大脑想不想计算一下畴壁的
How does your brain feel about calculating the surface tension
表面张力?
of the domain walls?
畴壁: 磁矩方向逐渐变化的过渡区域
我来看看
Let's see.
嘿! 我真的哼歌了
Hey! I was humming.
赫奇帕奇学院加一分
One point for Hufflepuff.
这是什么歌?
What song is that?
嗯... 你再哼一下
Well... hum it again.
是海绵宝宝的歌吗?
Is that the SpongeBob song?
# 住在大菠萝里 # 不是
# Who lives in a pineapple # Nope.
随便啦 我们可以继续算题吗?
Whatever. Can we just get back to this?
我觉得我应该知道这是什么歌
I feel like I know what song that is,
但就是想不起来了
but I can't put my finger on it.
# 我的国家属于你 # 不对
# My country, 'tis of thee # No.
只是耳虫现象 你会想起来的
It's just an earworm. It'll come to you.
耳虫: 某段音乐在脑中不断重复的现象
好吧
Okay.
# R-E-S-P-E-C-T # 不对
# R-E-S-P-E-C-T # No.
我们今晚就得这么过了吗?
Is this what we're doing the rest of the night?
# 惊讶你竟还要问... #
# I'm surprised you have to ask... #
* 宇宙一度又烫又稠密 *
* Our whole universe was in a hot, dense state *
* 140亿年前终于爆了炸... 等着瞧! *
* Then nearly 14 billion years ago expansion started... Wait! *
* 地球开始降温 *
* The Earth began to cool *
* 自养生物来起哄 穴居人发明工具 *
* The autotrophs began to drool, Neanderthals developed tools *
* 我们建长城 * * 我们建金字塔 *
* We built the Wall * * We built the pyramids *
* 数学 自然科学 历史 揭开神秘 *
* Math, Science, History, unraveling the mystery *
* 一切由大爆炸开始 *
* That all started with a big bang *
生活大爆炸 第九季第10集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 酥酥消失在雾霾里   校对: UUUUUU消失在雾霾里
翻译: 焦糖影 肉肉君 凤梨酥 舒大卷子 無限月讀
你好 我希望你能帮我个忙
Hello, yes, I was hoping you could help me.
这是哪首歌?
What song is this?
你不知道?
You don't know?
你们还有什么脸自称是
Well, how dare you call yourselves
"摇滚名人堂"?
a Rock and Roll Hall of Fame?
天啊 你就是用那张嘴跟唱
My goodness. Do you sing along to the greatest hits
猫王最著名的歌的?
of Elvis Presley with that mouth?
- 他们根本帮不上忙  - 不科学啊
- Well, they were no help at all.  - Which is crazy,
摇滚不是应该做客服的吗
since rock and roll is all about good customer service.
好了 你脑子里有首歌挥之不去
Yeah. So you have a song stuck in your head.
大家都有这经历
It happens to everybody.
我可不是普通人 我过目不忘
Well, I'm not everybody. I have an eidetic memory.
我应该是可以想起这是什么歌的
I should be able to remember what song this is,
但想不起来了
but I can't.
我出问题了
Something's wrong with me.
我跟你说过 只要我们耐心点 他自己总会发现的
I told you if we were patient, he'd figure it out for himself.
哦... 我一直很担心会有这么一天
Oh... I was always afraid this day would come.
这也许就是我坠入疯狂的第一步
This might be the first step of my descent into madness,
从此以后就慢慢去挑战公共场合的裸露极限了
where I gradually test the limits of public nudity.
公共场合裸露?
Public nudity?
他也就顶多打个赤脚
Eh, that just means going barefoot.
- 喂?  - 你好 Dave
- Hello?  - Hi, Dave.
我是Amy
Uh, it's Amy.
- 哦 你好吗?  - 我很好 你呢?
- Oh. How are you?  - I'm fine. How are you?
我很好 鉴于我在上次约会时的表现
Terrific. And pleasantly surprised to hear from you,
我很惊讶你竟然给我打电话了
given how I acted on our last date.
好吧
Yeah, well,
要知道我们都犯了错误
we both made mistakes, you know.
我吃掉了最后一根面包棒 你滔滔不绝说我前男友的事
I took the last breadstick, you gushed over my ex-boyfriend
好像他是伦纳德·尼莫伊 你才是我前男友一样
like he was Leonard Nimoy and you were my ex-boyfriend.
伦纳德·尼莫伊: "星际旅行"著名演员 已过世
那你打电话来有什么事?
So, to what do I owe the pleasure?
我在想
Well, I was wondering
你愿不愿意再跟我共进晚餐一次
if you'd like to get dinner again sometime.
当然可以
Yes, please.
- 太好了  - 让我先查查
- Great.  - Let me just check
我的日程表 他说
my schedule, he said,
还假装他的日程表上面有安排似的
trying to seem like a man with things on his schedule.
星期六怎么样?
How 'bout Saturday?
呃...
Uh, hmm...
我来看看 星期五
Let me see. Uh, Friday,
和Jay Z(歌手)去农贸市场
farmers' market with Jay Z.
星期天 和艾尔顿·约翰(歌手)去买钢琴
Sunday, piano shopping with Elton John.
星期六有空
Saturday works.
哦 你知道联合国有一个
Oh. Did you know, at the United Nations,
处理外太空事务的外交部吗?
there's a Department for Outer Space Affairs?
真的吗? 为什么?
Really? Why?
他们是为人类接触外星文明
They exist in case we ever make contact
而建立的
with an alien civilization.
嗯 这种工作就是 超无聊 超乏味
Mm, boy, that's one of those jobs that's boring, boring,
超无趣 突然"哦 天啊!
boring, then, "Oh, God!
我们的行动章程在哪?!现在咋办"
Where's the memo with what we do now?!"
哦 这个不错啊
Oh, this is cool.
几星期前 我在Facebook上建了一个
So, a few weeks ago, I set up a fan page
- 我们乐队的粉丝主页并...  - 等等
- on Facebook for our band and...  - Wait a second.
你怎么没经我同意就建主页了?
How could you do that without consulting me?
这又没什么大不了
It's not a big deal.
建个主页也就差不多五分钟
It just took, like, five minutes to set up.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
当初创立月球上的脚印的时候
When we created Footprints on the Moon,
我们说好每个决定都一起做的
we agreed that every band decision would be mutual.
现在你自作主张
Now you're just trying to take over the whole thing.
我还是单干吧
You know, maybe I should go solo.
但是有人关注我们的主页了
But someone joined our page.
我们有正式的粉丝了
We have an actual fan.
好吧
All right.
乐队比咱俩要重要 我回归了
This thing's bigger than you and me. Band's back together.
听听他写了什么
So, listen to what he wrote.
嗯 "我看到你们在漫画店的表演了
Uh, "I saw you play at the comic book store.
你们可真酷"
You guys rock."
还有一个像这样高举双手
And then there's a animated smiley face
的动态表情...
raising the roof like this...
那天我们确实让很多人都高举双手了
We did raise the roof that night.
- 当然  - 这感觉这么好
- Yeah, we totally did.  - Why do rock stars
摇滚明星们为什么要去嗑药?
do drugs when this feels so great?
# 我为什么想不起来这首歌? #
# Why can't I recall this song? #
# 这已经花费我太多时间了 #
# This is taking far too long. #
# 迫使我把头不停不停不停不停地 #
# The urge to bang my head against the wall #
# 撞上墙的念头十分强烈 #
# Again and again and again and again and again is strong. #
- 把耳机戴上吧  - # 不 #
- Put on some headphones.  - # No #
# 他们会让我耳垂出汗 #
# They make my earlobes sweat. #
嗯 亲爱的 要不你歇歇
Uh, sweetie, why don't you take a break
然后干些别的事?
and do something else for a while?
我正考虑开始一个项目
There was a project I've been thinking about starting.
哦 不错 是什么?
Okay, great. What is it?
我会给你看的
I'll show you.
亲爱的疯狂的未来Sheldon
Dear Crazy Future Sheldon,
你已经被耳虫逼疯了
you were driven mad by an earworm.
你曾经最信任的权威 你的大脑
Your mind, once your most trusted asset,
已经被鹦鹉和猴子所侵袭了
is now a sack of parrots and monkeys.
所以...
So...
我要告诉你所有你需要知道的事情
I'm going to tell you everything you need to know.
嗯 首先 音乐很危险
Uh, first, music is dangerous.
电影浑身是劲试图警告我们 但我们没有听
The movie Footloose tried to warn us, but we wouldn't listen.
哦 等等 # 大家都无拘无... #
Oh, wait. # Everybody cut footloo... #
不是
Nope.
我愿意付一千刀看你无拘无束跳舞的样子
I'll pay $1,000 to watch you cut footloose.
这是Penny
This is Penny.
她是你的朋友
She is your friend.
如果她给你吃的 你可以放心接受
If she offers you food, it's safe to take it.
反正你可能已经给了她钱了
You probably paid for it, anyway.
所以 你真的要再和Dave约会一次吗?
So, you're really going out with Dave again?
为什么不呢?
Why not?
他其实是个很好的人
He's actually a very nice guy.
但整个约会
But he spent an entire date
他都在谈他有多喜欢Sheldon
talking about how much he loves Sheldon.
反正Sheldon也这样
That's nothing Sheldon hasn't done before.
Dave只是他的一个狂热粉丝罢了
Dave's just a big fan of his work.
还有 他说他不会再提这事了
Besides, he said he wouldn't bring it up again.
好吧 那么他准备带你去哪里?
Okay. So where's he taking you?
哦 他要来这里 我来做饭
Oh, he's coming here. I'm actually making dinner.
哦 进展很快啊
Oh. That's a big step.
快吗?
It is?
当然 你把他邀请到家里
Yeah. You're inviting him into your home.
这是很亲密的举动
It's intimate.
这可是你的内内们住的地方
It's where your underpants live.
其实 这样挺好
You know what? Good.
我试着和Sheldon复合 但是他拒绝了
I tried to get back together with Sheldon. He shot me down.
Dave喜欢我
Dave likes me.
也许亲密才是我需要的
Maybe intimate is what I need.
你确定吗?
You sure?
你从来没有和男人认真交往过
You've never really been with a man.
你真的想从这个两米高的男人开始吗?
Do you really want to start with one that's six-foot-seven?
为何不行?
Why not?
就像你不会开巴士去考驾照啊
'Cause it's like taking your driver's test in a bus.
我们应该回复那个粉丝并感谢他
Maybe we should post a comment back to our fan and thank him.
我们该写什么?
What should we write?
嗯... 嗯...
How 'bout, uh... Oh, how 'bout,
"我们可能是月球上的脚印
"We might be Footprints on the Moon,
但你的赞扬会让我们飞跃月球"
but your kind words sent us over the moon."
你真是一点新意都没有 像个老奶奶一样
Someday you're gonna make an amazing grandma.
那你想写什么?
What do you want to write?
写点坏坏的话 比如...
Something bad-ass, you know, like...
"谢谢你喜欢我们的范儿
"Thanks for digging our vibe.
"只要有你支持我们
"We'll keep rocking
我们就会一直摇滚下去"
if you keep rolling."
哥们 要是我也穿文胸的话
Dude, if I was wearing a bra,
现在一定脱下来扔到你头上
I'd throw it at your head right now.
我继续摇滚 不过你可别真这么干
I'll keep rocking. You don't do that.
我回复了
Okay. I posted it.
这个人是谁啊
So, who is this guy?
我看看 他叫Trent Monaco
Let's see. Uh, his name is Trent Monaco.
- 名字不错  - 是啊
- Cool name.  - Yeah.
今年24岁 说自己是个打碟的
He's 24. He's a deejay.
他自己酿啤酒
He brews his own beer. He's got
还有超赞的纹身 他还有个蛮漂亮的女朋友
awesome tattoos. Dude, he's got a hot girlfriend, too.
靠 我都不知道谁是谁的粉丝了
Damn. I don't know if he's our biggest fan or I'm his.
嘿 Trent刚刚给我们的回复点赞了
Hey, Trent just liked our comment.
他太酷了!
He is so cool!
别觉得不爽
No hard feelings,
不过我打算要把假想文胸扔给他了
but I'm throwing my hypothetical bra at him.
哦 天啊 他真的是根本停不下来
Oh, my God, he won't stop.
为什么他总能变着花样儿的招人烦?
How does he keep coming up with new ways to be annoying?
没人知道 所以他才无人能敌
Nobody knows. That's why he's number one.
你能去跟他谈谈吗?
Can you please go talk to him?
拜托 白天一整天都是我看着他 你也去一次行不行
Come on. I take care of him all day long. You do it for once.
一次? 是谁帮他清理头发里的口香糖的?
Once? Who got the gum out of his hair?
你想让我夸你吗? 那是你的口香糖啊
What do you want, a medal? It was your gum.
好吧
Fine.
我爱你
I love you.
谁稀罕?
Who cares?
你来我房间干什么? 我...
What are you doing in my room? I...
你住手! 那是我的!
Stop it! That's mine!
你怎么这么有劲?!
Why are you so strong?!
搞定
Problem solved.
对了 他还有个大号
Oh, yeah, he got a tuba.
未来的疯Sheldon...
Dear Crazy Future Sheldon...
这是中央空调控制
this is a thermostat.
它可以调节公寓里的温度
It controls the temperature of the apartment.
最适宜的温度是72华氏度
The ideal setting is 72 degrees.
要是你觉得冷 就穿一件外套
If you find this too cold, then put on a jacket.
干脆穿束身衣吧 因为72度最合适了 而你是真的疯了
A straitjacket, because 72's the best and you're crazy.
这里...
Now... this...
是你的位置
is your spot.
你对这个位置有超强的保护欲
You're very protective of it.
要是别人想坐在这里
When anyone else tries to sit here,
你一定要无情地赶走他们
you berate them relentlessly.
听起来这样有点过分 但是不知道为什么 你这么干也挺可爱的
It sounds mean, but somehow you make it adorable.
人们也喜欢你那些小恶作剧
People are also delighted by your love of pranks.
比如 Leonard完全不知道
For example, Leonard has no idea
我对他的咖啡做了什么
what I did to his coffee.
我并没有"换上Folger's Crystals"
It wasn't "replace it with Folger's crystals,"
我只能说这么多了
I'll tell you that much.
嘿 你能过来工作吗?
Hey, can we please get back to work?
这是Leonard
This is Leonard.
他是你最好的朋友
He's your best friend in the world.
够了 停下吧 这太荒唐了
All right, just stop. This is ridiculous.
有时候他脾气不太好
Sometimes he gets cranky,
不过你可以完全信任他
but you can trust him with your life.
他为你做过的事情 数都数不清
And he does more things for you than I can even begin to list.
谢了
Thank you.
哦! 他喝了咖啡!
Oh, no, he's drinking it.
你看 你看
Look at this.
Trent在修一个复古摩托车
Trent is rebuilding a vintage motorcycle.
太酷了
Hmm. That is so cool!
已经坏了的旧东西总是
Old broken things are so much better
比新的好用的东西更值钱
than new things that work.
谁是Trent?
Who's Trent?
哦 他是我们的粉丝
Oh, he's our fan.
- 什么粉丝?  - 呃...
- Fan of what?  - Uh...
你忘了吗? 我们有个乐队的
Did you forget? We're in a band.
就是只在漫画店演出过一次的那个乐队?
You mean because you played one time in the comic book store?
我们还去儿童医院演出过 不过后来被赶出来了
And at the children's hospital until they asked us to leave.
嘿
Hey,
Trent刚才在Fair Oak那家咖啡馆签到了
dude, Trent just checked in at the coffee shop on Fair Oaks.
真的? 你想不想去那里见见他?
Really? You want to go down there and meet him?
你们在跟踪他? 这太奇葩了吧
Are you stalking him? That's creepy.
这才不奇葩
It's not creepy.
我给"月亮上的脚印"建了一个粉丝主页 Trent加入了
I built a Footprints on the Moon fan page, Trent joined it.
后来 我就是看了看他的资料
After that, all I did was check out his profile,
翻了翻他以前发过的东西
go back in the archive of his feed
就找到了他推特的链接
until I found his Twitter handle.
然后就很容易在Instagram和Snapchat上找到他了啊
From there, it was easy to find him on Instagram, Snapchat
基本上可以追踪他的每一个行动
and pretty much track his every movement.
要是你觉得这样很奇葩 那你可就嫁错人了
So if you think that's creepy, you married the wrong guy.
可能我应该嫁给Trent
Maybe I should marry Trent.
是啊 她还觉得Trent能看上她呢
Yeah, like she could get Trent.
很美味
This is delicious.
谢谢
Thank you.
我很久没吃过家常便餐了
Been a long time since I had a home-cooked meal.
以前你已婚的时候 你妻子煮菜吗?
When you were married, did your wife cook?
一开始不煮
Not at first, no.
但当她出轨了法国主厨以后
But when she began cheating on me with a French chef,
她变成了厨房奇才
she became quite the wiz in the kitchen.
不幸中的万幸
So, a little silver lining.
我想是的
I suppose.
是啊 没有什么比一碗美味的洋葱汤
Yeah. Nothing takes the sting out of a shattered life
更能让人从破碎的生活中脱离出来
like a properly-seasoned bowl of onion soup.
你在这里 住了多久了?
How long have you, uh, lived here?
差不多五年了
About five years.
我在考虑搬到更好的地方去
I'm actually thinking of moving to a better place
现在我不再需要靠近...
now that I don't need to be so close to...
你知道的是谁
Well, you know.
我知道 那位杰出的物理学家
I do. The brilliant physicist
我知道他就住在这一片 不是我在意这些
that I now know lives in the area, not that I care.
是的 总之 他不会开车
Yeah. Anyway, he doesn't drive,
所以我几乎必须 开车带他去任何地方
so, I pretty much had to take him everywhere.
必须还是可以?
Had to or got to?
抱歉
Sorry.
我的错 是我惯出来的
My fault. I brought him up. Yeah.
我们换个话题
Well, let's change the subject.
不要再提那个人
No more mentions of you-know-who.
那个火车好酷
That's a cool train.
你从哪里得来的?
Where did you get that?
# 梆 梆 梆...梆 梆梆梆 #
# Bah, bah, bum-bum, bah, bum, bum. #
这个歌
This song
停不下来了
is never going to stop.
你们有处理过
Have you ever dealt with something
这么持续烦人的东西吗?
so relentlessly irritating?
这是逗我呢 对吧?
That's a trick question, right?
我不应该感到意外的
Well, I shouldn't be surprised.
聪明的头脑陷入疯狂
There's a rich history of
的历史相当悠久
brilliant minds descending into madness.
得了 Sheldon
Come on, Sheldon.
有很多聪明人没有精神方面的问题
There are plenty of smart people who don't have mental problems.
她说的对
Yup, she's right.
对于每个有心理问题的牛顿
For every Newton who had a psychological issue,
都有一个仅仅只是混蛋的爱迪生
there's an Edison who was just a jerk.
你完全可以是这种
That could totally be you.
恩培多克勒(哲学家)觉得自己是神然后跳进了火山
Empedocles thought he was a god and jumped into a volcano.
And Pythagoras had
毕达哥拉斯
对豆子有非理性恐惧
an irrational fear of beans.
特斯拉(物理学家)疯狂的爱上了一只鸽子
Tesla fell madly in love with a pigeon
一只他声称也爱他的鸽子
who he claimed loved him back.
可能只是因为他口袋里放了面包
Maybe he just had bread in his pocket.
这个名单延伸到科学界之外
The list extends outside of science.
梵高和波洛克这样的画家
Painters like Van Gogh and Pollock,
博比·菲舍尔 国际象棋冠军
chess champion Bobby Fischer,
Brian Wilson 沙滩男孩...
Brian Wilson of the Beach Boy...
# 知道如果语言可以表达#
# Know if words could say #
# 但是亲爱的 我会找到方法... #
# But darlin', I'll find a way... #
我想起这首歌了!
I remember the song!
它是沙滩男孩的"亲爱的"
It's called "Darlin'" by the Beach Boys!
哦 谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness!
我没有疯!
I'm not crazy!
我不需要让一只鸽子成为我的恋人了!
I don't have to take a pigeon as my bride!
我们错失了让他生活在屋顶上的机会
There goes our shot at him living on the roof.
他就在那里
So, all right, there he is.
我们应该去自我介绍吗?
So, should we introduce ourselves?
不! 让他发现我们
No! Let him spot us.
我想知道
I wonder
他现在是不是正在听我们的音乐
if he's listening to our music right now.
你可以想象吗?
Could you imagine?
那样我们的见面该有多酷啊
What a cool way for us to meet.
他在听着我们的歌 然后抬起头 我们就在这里...
He's playing our song and looks up, and there we are...
他最喜欢的科幻新奇两件套乐队
his favorite two-piece acoustic sci-fi novelty rock band.
然后他就 像
And he's, all, like,
"你们是月球上的脚印...?"
"Aren't you the guys from Footprints on the Moo...?"
哦 他在干什么?!
Ooh, what is he doing?!
我看不下去了
I can't watch.
没 没关系
I... It's okay.
没关系 他弄好了
Oh, it's okay. He's done.
他为什么看着它?!
Why is he looking at it?!
不会 他不会吃掉它的 会吗?
Eh, no, he's not going to eat it, is he?
加油 Trent 你不是这样的人
Come on, Trent, you're better than...
我们赶紧走吧
Let's just go.
嘿 你们是...?
Hey, aren't you the guys...?
不是? 从来没听过!
Nope! Never heard of 'em!
# ...知道如果语言可以表达 #
# ...Know if words could say #
# 但是亲爱的 我会找到方法... #
# But darlin', I'll find a way... #
我想知道为什么这首歌
I wonder why it was this particular song
会一直停留在脑中
that was stuck in my head.
我不知道 挺洗脑的
I don't know. It's pretty catchy.
你真有喜欢海滩小子吗?
Do you even like the Beach Boys?
他们的名字里就有"海滩"俩字儿呢
They have "beach" right in the name.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
既然你现在又能认真工作了，要不然
Well, now that you can focus again, what do you say
我们再来看看磁壁的表面张力问题吧?
we get back to surface tension of domain walls?
没问题 我已经想到了更有效的方法
Of course. I'm already seeing a more efficient way
来驯服紫外...
of taming the ultravi...
我知道为什么脑子里不停响这首歌了
I know why the song was in my head.
- 为什么?  - 歌是关于Amy的
- Why?  - It's about Amy.
好吧 我知道Amy像个老妈妈
Okay, look, I know Amy's like an old lady,
可她也不至于老到
but she's not old enough to have a song
有首60年代的歌是写她的
from the '60s written about her.
歌里写了她如何让我的人生更美好
It's about how she made my life better.
来看看歌词
Consider the lyrics.
"我的人生不曾完整
"I was living like half a man.
"彼时无爱 此刻深情
"Then I couldn't love, but now I can.
"造就了
"More soul than
一个无比丰富灵魂
"I ever had.
"我爱你 温柔了我的岁月"
I love the way you soften my life."
她的确温柔了你的岁月 不是吗?
Well, she did soften your life, didn't she?
就是呀!
Yes!
她就像我心灵的干燥巾!
She's like the dryer sheets of my heart!
干燥纸:烘干衣服时和衣服一起放进去的干燥纸巾
我得走了
I have to go.
噢
Aw.
我是你心灵的干燥巾吗?
Am I like the dryer sheets of your heart?
比那还好 你是我爱情的过滤网
Better. You're the lint trap of my love.
过滤网:洗衣机下水管前面的过滤网
噢
Aw.
领带夹不错呀
That's an interesting tie clip.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
上面印的是亚弗加厥常数
It's, uh, Avogadro's constant.
计算物质原子量的时候蛮有用的
It's useful for calculating the number of atoms in a substance,
不过问的人就会觉得无聊了
or causing regret in anyone who asks about it.
呃 我...
Oh, I...
我觉得蛮漂亮的
I think it's neat.
噢! 抱歉 抱歉
Oh! Sorry. Sorry.
以前没人喜欢这个领带夹
No one's ever liked the tie clip before,
然后我就失态了 我...
so I just lost all control. I...
没... 没事的 我们正约会呢
No, it... it's okay, and we are on a date.
我...我有点儿紧张
I'm... I'm just a little nervous.
呃 和我一起没必要紧张
Well, no need to be nervous with me.
我只是国外来的人畜无害的大个子
I'm just a harmless giant from a foreign land.
你看 我只是在犯傻 我...
You know, I'm just being silly. I...
我不知道我期待的是什么
I don't know what I'm waiting for.
Amy在吗?
Amy?
Amy在吗
Amy.
Amy在吗?
Amy?
是Sheldon
That's Sheldon.
你搞笑吧! 我发型还行吧?
You're kidding! How's my hair?
Sheldon 现在见你不太合适
Sheldon, this-this isn't a good time.
我才不管
I don't care.
Amy 我脑子里不停的响着一首歌
Amy, there was a song I couldn't get out of my head.
终于 我意识到这首歌是关于你的
Eventually, I realized the song was about you,
就像耳虫一样 我心里也忘不了你
and like that earworm, I can't get you out of my heart.
所以 我想说的是
So, what I'm trying to say is,
你是我的心虫
you're my heartworm.
比喻意义上的 不是有害的那种
The metaphorical kind, not-not the poodle-killing kind.
什...么?
W-W-W-What?
我插一句...
If I may...
我想他要说的是
I believe what he's saying,
充满了美好而甜蜜的意思
in a charming and delightful way,
他爱你 并且想让你回到他身边
is that he loves you and wants you back.
我是Dave Gibbs 很喜欢你事业上的成就
Dave Gibbs, huge fan of your work.
噢 别管我
Oh. Don't mind me.
抱...抱歉 我不知道你正在约会
I'm... I'm sorry; I didn't realize you were on a date.
没...没事的 继续说下去?
No, it... it... it's okay. Keep going?
Amy 如果你愿意再当我女朋友的话
Amy, if you want to be my girlfriend again,
我很愿意当你的男朋友
I really want to be your boyfriend.
我也很愿意
I really want that, too.
太好了 因为我爱你
Good. Because I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
吻她 你个聪明的小傻瓜!
Kiss her, you brilliant fool!
呃...
Well...
你们还是继续约会吧
I'll let you get back to your date.
回来吧!
Get back here!
# 噢~~~ 亲爱的 #
# Oh, oh, oh, darlin' #
# 梦里都是你 我的美人 #
# I dream about you often, my pretty darlin' #
# 我爱你温柔了我的... #
# I love the way you soften my... #
好吧 那么
Okay, then.
我就 呃 不要你们送了
I'll, uh, see myself out.
Amy 谢谢你的晚饭
Amy, thank you for dinner.
Cooper博士 很高兴见到你
Dr. Cooper, pleasure to meet you, sir.
如果什么时候你有空的话
Uh, if perhaps sometime you have a spare moment,
我愿意跟你探讨下物理
I'd, uh, love-love to discuss physics,
或者是"吹吹牛皮" 按你们美国人的说法
or "shoot the breeze," as you Yanks say.
晚上过的很愉快呀
Ah. What a lovely evening.